avm.de 2019-12-24

# Privacy Policy | AVM International

Our our web and online presence we also offer the possibility of registering for our newsletter; advertising tools and social media plug-ins are used as well. Specifically:

#### 1\. Newsletter Registration and Competitions

If you would like to take advantage of the newsletter or take part in competitions, we need you to confirm your valid email address. In order to check whether you are the owner of the given email address, or that the address's owner consents to receiving the newsletter or taking part in competitions, after the first registration step we will send an automated email to the given email address ("double opt-in"). Only after confirmation of the newsletter registration or participation in the competition via a confirmation link in the email will we include the given email address in our mailing list. We do not collect any data other than the email address and the information that the registration has been confirmed. 

Your data are processed exclusively for the purpose of mailing the newsletter you requested. The legal basis for this processing is Article 6(1b) of the GDPR. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time; in addition, the remarks on the right of revocation in (III.4) apply. 

If you win as part of a competition, we will contact you at the email address provided to determine the mailing address for sending the prize. 

#### 2\. Use of Personalized Data for Promotional Pitches and Marketing Messages / Customer Surveys

Your personalized data are used for the purpose of advertising and/or marketing and for the purpose of performing customer satisfaction surveys only when corresponding permission has been granted, or when there is another legal basis that permits advertising or marketing messages even without express consent. 

The legal foundation for advertising and/or marketing measures on the basis of express consent is Article 6 (1a) of the GDPR; correspondingly, the remarks on consent in (III) apply. The legal basis for the use of personal data for the purpose of direct marketing by post is Art. 6 (1f) of the GDPR (legitimate interest); the legitimate interest here consists in addressing potential customers for the purpose of direct advertising for our products and services. For advertising and/or marketing measures via email for the purpose of direct advertising for similar wares or services of our own, the legal basis is Section 7(3) of the German Fair Trade Practices Act (UWG); this is subject to the condition that (i) we received your email address in connection with the sale of a good or service, (ii) you did not refuse to allow your email address to be used for the purpose of direct advertising and (iii) upon the collection of your email address and every time we use it, we clearly point out that you may refuse at any time to have your email address used in this way (on the right to refuse, see [XI.6]). 

Your personal data will be stored and used for advertising purposes indefinitely, depending on the respective legal basis for the advertising measure (consent or legitimate interest), until you object to the use of your data for advertising purposes or until you revoke your corresponding consent. You can revoke consent to a processing of personal data at any time, with effect for the future. You may object to processing on the basis of legitimate interests at any time; a right of objection exists in particular in the case of profiling in accordance with Art. 21 of the GDPR. In the event of revocation and/or objection, the personal data will no longer be processed for the purposes concerned; with the exception of processing of data which is still required for the purpose of fulfilling the contract (Art. 6 (1b) of the GDPR) including statutory storage obligations and/or if the data is still required within the framework of legitimate interests (Art. 6 (1b) GDPR) (e.g. in the event of an advertising objection, processing of data in a so-called blacklist in order to prevent future advertising approaches). 

#### 3\. Interest-based ads e.g. Amazon Tracking Pixel

AVM uses third-party service providers, such as Amazon, to optimize our online ads by anonymously collecting and processing your usage patterns based on predicted interests. For this purpose Amazon uses cookies on your computer (please refer to section VI above) to anonymously record your usage data when you visit our website. In this way, we can analyze the use of online ads and provide you with ads that are more useful and relevant. Under no circumstances will personal data (such as name, address, email address) be stored. IP addresses are anonymized, meaning the user cannot be personally identified. To customize your preferences, visit the [Amazon Advertising Preferences](https://www.amazon.de/adprefs/ref=ya__39) page. 

Interest-based online ads are provided by the named third-party service provider. If you no longer wish to receive usage-based advertising, you can deactivate the data collection by switching off cookies (please refer to section VI.3 for more informaton) or by setting up an opt-out cookie. For more information on Amazon cookie usage, visit the [Amazon Interest-Based Ads](https://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=hp_left_v4_sib?ie=UTF8&nodeId=201909150) page. 

#### 4\. Analytics and marketing tools e.g. Adform

We use analytics and marketing tools on our websites, such as the Adform tool from the company Adform A/S (1. sal. K, Wildersgade 10B, 1408 Copenhagen, Denmark), which collects data for analytics,marketing and optimization purposes e.g. to improve the offering of our websites and advertising campaigns. We use Adform to determine whether users who have seen our adverts subsequently visit our website or are interested in our products. The data collected can also be used by us to deliver advertising based on your interests (e.g. products viewed). Pseudonymous online ID numbers (online ID) are used when collecting data, such as cookie IDs, IP address or device IDs. During this process, no user-related data, such as name or address, are saved. All of the IDs used by us are solely for the purpose of recognizing your end device or browser. The data collected will not be used to personally identify you as a user of our website without your separate consent. The legal basis for this data processing is Article 6 (1a and 1f) of the GDPR. If you don't want Adform to collect data, you can click on the link below for instructions on how to deactivate the collection of data on your end device: 

<https://site.adform.com/privacy-policy-opt-out/>

#### 5\. Social Networks / Social Media Plug-ins 

On our web pages we have embedded buttons ("plug-ins") to the social network YouTube so that you can enjoy the interactive potentials of the social networks you use on our web pages as well. With this plug-in we embed video contents in the website. This makes various functions available, the object and extent of which are determined by the operators of the social networks. Keep in mind that the IP address of your browser session may be linked to your own profile with the given social network if you are currently logged in to that network. Similarly, your visit to our web pages can be linked to your profile with the social network if it recognizes you from a cookie that was set during a previous session with the social network and is still stored on your computer. 

**Please note that we are not the provider of the social networks and thus have no influence on data processing by the given provider. More information on data handling is available at Google's Privacy Policy, for example.**

#### 5.1. Facebook

Our pages have not embedded any plug-ins from the social network Facebook, 1601 South California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. There is merely a passive link to our contents on Facebook. 

On certain web pages (en.avm.de/news, for instance), the contents of our Facebook pages can be played via plug-in. The use of user data is not connected with these contents. 

If you contact us and interact with us on Facebook (requests, "like" button, comments, etc.), be it for the purpose of support requests, sales queries, requests regarding the company (for instance, in the context of applicant management), press queries, or in order to send us feedback, we use tools that process the user data generated by Facebook in order to process these requests. Insofar as this involves the processing of personalized data, Article 6(1b) of the GDPR is the legal basis. 

#### 5.2. Google+

Our pages have not embedded any plug-ins from the social network "Google+". There is merely a passive link to our contents on Google+. 

If you contact us and interact with us on Google+ (requests, "like" button, comments, etc.), be it for the purpose of support requests, sales queries, requests regarding the company (for instance, in the context of applicant management), press queries, or in order to send us feedback, we use tools that process the user data generated by Google+ in order to process these requests. Insofar as this involves the processing of personalized data, Article 6(1b) of the GDPR is the legal basis. 

#### 5.3. Twitter

Our pages have not embedded any functions from the social network "Twitter". There is merely a passive link to our contents on Twitter. 

If you contact us and interact with us on Twitter (requests, "like" button, comments, etc.), be it for the purpose of support requests, sales queries, requests regarding the company (for instance, in the context of applicant management), press queries, or in order to send us feedback, we use tools that process the user data generated by Twitter in order to process these requests. Insofar as this involves the processing of personalized data, Article 6(1b) of the GDPR is the legal basis. 

#### 5.4. LinkedIn

Our pages have not embedded any functions from the social network "LinkedIn". There is merely a passive link to our contents on TwitterThere is merely a passive link to our contents on LinkedIn. 

If you contact us and interact with us on LinkedIn (requests, "like" button, comments, etc.), be it for the purpose of support requests, sales queries, requests regarding the company (for instance, in the context of applicant management), press queries, or in order to send us feedback, we use tools that process the user data generated by LinkedIn in order to process these requests. Insofar as this involves the processing of personalized data, Article 6(1b) of the GDPR is the legal basis. 

#### 5.5. XING

Our pages have not embedded any functions from the "XING" service, which is operated by XING AG, Gänsemarkt 43, 20354 Hamburg, Germany. There is merely a passive link to our contents on XING. 

If you contact us and interact with us on XING (requests, "like" button, comments, etc.), be it for the purpose of support requests, sales queries, requests regarding the company (for instance, in the context of applicant management), press queries, or in order to send us feedback, we use tools that process the user data generated by XING in order to process these requests. Insofar as this involves the processing of personalized data, Article 6(1b) of the GDPR is the legal basis. 

If you enable and use the plug-in, your browser establishes a direct connection to the XING servers. The contents of the plug-in are transmitted by XING directly to your browser and integrated into the web pages. When the plug-in is activated, XING receives the information that you opened the corresponding page of our website. If you are logged in to XING, XING can match the visit to your XING account. The purpose and scope of data collection and the further processing and use of the data by XING, as well as your rights in this regard and settings options to protect your privacy are presented in the XING [Privacy Policy](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy). 

#### 5.6 YouTube

We use the provider YouTube to integrate videos (FRITZ! Clips etc.) on our web pages. YouTube is operated by YouTube LLC with headquarters at 901 Cherry Avenue, San Bruno, CA 94066, USA. YouTube is represented by Google Inc., based at 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. 

On some pages we also use a YouTube plug-in. When you open a page equipped with such a plug-in, a connection to the YouTube servers is established automatically to render the plug-in. In the process, which of our web pages you visited is conveyed to the YouTube server. If you are a member of YouTube and logged in to YouTube when you visit our page, YouTube can match this information to your personal user account. When you use the plug-in, for instance, by clicking the Start button on a video, this information is also matched to your user account. You can prevent such information from being matched by deregistering from, or logging out of, your YouTube user account and other user accounts with the companies YouTube LLC and/or Google Inc. before using our web pages. Alternatively, you can delete the relevant cookies set by these companies (see [VI.3] for instructions). Further information on data processing and data protection by YouTube (Google) is available at [policies.google.com/privacy](http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/)

If you contact us and interact with us on YouTube (requests, "like" button, comments, etc.), be it for the purpose of support requests, sales queries, requests regarding the company (for instance, in the context of applicant management), press queries, or in order to send us feedback, we use tools that process the user data generated by YouTube in order to process these requests. Insofar as this involves the processing of personalized data, Article 6(1b) of the GDPR is the legal basis. 

#### 5.7 Instagram

Our pages do not include any "social plug-ins" from Instagram, which is operated by Instagram LLC., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA. There is merely a passive link to our contents on Instagram. 

If you contact us and interact with us on Instagram (requests, "like" button, comments, etc.), be it for the purpose of support requests, sales queries, requests regarding the company (for instance, in the context of applicant management), press queries, or in order to send us feedback, we use tools that process the user data generated by Instagram in order to process these requests. Insofar as this involves the processing of personalized data, Article 6(1b) of the GDPR is the legal basis. 

#### 6\. Messaging apps

As a subscriber to our instant messaging services, for example WhatsApp News, you will receive the latest updates and news directly to your smartphone or tablet. To register, AVM generally needs a phone number or similar. In order to check whether you are the owner of the phone number provided, or that the owner of the phone number consents to receiving the news updates, after the first registration step we will send an automated text message to the phone number provided (the so-called "double opt-in"). Save the sender of the message as a new contact in your smartphone or tablet. Only after you've sent a message to this contact e.g. "START" can we start sending you the latest updates and news. We do not collect any personal data other than the phone number and the information that the registration has been confirmed. Your data are processed exclusively for the purpose of providing with information about the latest news from AVM, as requested by you. The legal basis for this processing is Article 6 (1b) of the GDPR. You can unsubscribe from the news service at any time; in addition, the remarks on the right of revocation in (III.4) apply.
